ONKAR VAIDYA

Pune, Maharashtra | 7020752389 | onkarvaidyad789@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/onkar-vaidya/ | onkar2405.github.io/web-dev/

Profile

I am a software engineer who loves to make things. I'm experienced in Web development, and I can write clean, efficient, high quality code. I'm currently working as a lead developer and responsible for the delivery of team of 6 Web developers.

Experience

Raja Software Labs - Software Engineer

June 2021- Present

- LinkedIn Project:
 - Worked on LinkedIn's live website in the first two quarters.
 - Currently leading LinkedIn's Trust tools project. Managing the overall delivery of a team of 6 web developers while contributing to the code myself.
 - Took a major part in building the team to develop the Accessible UI(front-end) for 26 add-ons and 3
 applications from scratch using Ember.js with API integration. Wrote integration and unit test cases for the
 developed features.
 - Additionally, setting up tracking events, configuring Mirage, and lint setup to ensure adherence to best coding practices across all 3 applications and 26 add-ons with my team.
- TruePill Project:
 - Individual contributor responsible for delivering prime features for the live website.
 - Worked on updating and creating features with best code practices on the web-app using ReactJs and Rest APIs.

ShreeyanshDB Software - Software Engineer Intern

June 2019-Dec 2019

- Project was about data migration from MSSQL to PostgreSQL.
- Used Linux to write shell scripts and creating new Nagios plugins for the project.
- Database Assessment, Database Migration and Query Tuning Activity was part of the Role.

Skills

Programming Languages: Javascript, C++, SQL

Web Technologies: EmberJs, React beginner, REST APIs, HTML5, CSS, SASS, Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: JIRA, Git, Github, Linux **Cloud/Databases**: AWS, PostgreSQL **Coursework**: AWS Fundamentals, ReactJs

Technical Interests: Software Engineering, Cloud Computing, Web Developement

Projects

Resume Parser | NLP libraries Spacy, PDFMiner, and pandas

 Extract necessary Information from resume using regular expression and some pre-trained NLP libraries like Spacy, PDFMiner, and pandas.

Home Surveillance System | Python, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Facial Recognition

 Designed a Face Detection & Recognition System using Deep CNN to identify visitors as known or unknown with detection accuracy of 95%

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics & Telecommunication

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology — Pune, India

Higher Secondary Education(H.S.E.)

N.E.S. Science College — Pune, India

Aug 2016 to Oct 2020 CGPA: 8.96

Aug 2014 to Aug 2016

86%

Certifications

AWS Cloud Practitioner 2023

- Introductory course to learn the fundamentals of AWS.
- Learnt about cloud services like EC2, Security groups, S3, RDS, Load balancer, Lambda functions, RDS etc., and how cloud helps to scale faster and take business globally in no time.